Pavin Mathew

Luna Fukushima #301, Ebie 1-12-11, Fukushima, Osaka, Japan - (080) 9744-9224 Email: pavinmathew@gmail.com · www: pavinmathew.com · GitHub: github.com/pvmathew

SUMMARY

Prolific front-end programmer with years of experience designing and developing scalable React apps. Applies said experience in tandem with back-end frameworks such as Express to piece together full-stack applications on the regular. Demonstrates a high level of proficiency with a wide variety of third-party modules, component libraries, and API.

SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript DevOps: Git, GitHub Actions, Docker

Frameworks: React, Redux, Next.js, Express Databases: MongoDB, Firebase, PostgreSQL

Testing: Jest, React Testing Library, Cypress **Other:** Slack, ZenHub, XD, Figma

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sure Innovation - Frontend Developer

2021 - Present

- Worked closely with PM, Designer, and Engineer team to meet project requirements, goals, and desired functionality.
- Managed 3 different React apps from initial design process through completion, optimizing browser performance across all devices.
- Lead continuous testing efforts for every project via extensive unit & integration test coverage.

JET Programme - Assistant Language Teacher (ALT)

2017 - 2021

- Communicated closely with staff and students between 10 schools to teach and raise English standard; improved language proficiency of Japanese students through self-developed and personalized curriculum.
- Provided official translation of city hall documents, from Japanese to English.

Personal Projects (2019-)

PicrossO - Picross Online

- Designed and developed multiplayer picross web app that allows users to join and host custom games. Equipped with real time communication and click detection for cooperative play.
- Completely server rendered React front-end with fully functional declarative routing.
- Tech Stack: React, React Router, Socket.io, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, i18n.js

New Horizons Trading Club

• Built a web portal for Animal Crossing players to list & trade in-game items. Includes working item search that utilizes community maintained database with all item variations.

Graduation: Spring 2017

Tech Stack: React, Node.js, Express, Mongoose (MongoDB), JWT

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science – Computer Science and Japanese University of California, Davis 2012-2017 Kyoto Seika University 2015

CERTIFICATIONS

• Japanese Language Proficiency Test - N1